I see…
(ヒルゼン)そうですか
別空間に ナルトと サスケ。
Sasuke and Naruto are in
an alternate Time-Space
それに サクラとカカシも。
as well as Sakura and Kakashi.
(ハゴロモ)ナルトと サスケが
主体となって戦っておる。
Naruto and Sasuke are
the core participants in the battle.
I wish we could have gotten
your advice and aid a bit earlier.
(扉間)助言をいただけるなら→
もっと早くに
してほしかったですね。
(ハゴロモ)この下半身は→
This lower body is a part of Madara
after he became the Ten Tails' Jinchuriki.
十尾の人柱力になったあとの
マダラの一部。
つまり 十尾と マダラと 柱間。
In short, it contains Ten Tails,
Madara and Hashirama…
いや 九尾と マダラと 柱間。
No, rather Nine Tails, Madara
and Hashirama.
いや 九尾と インドラと アシュラ。
No, rather Nine Tails,
Indra and Ashura.
そのチャクラが 今 やっと揃い
わしが出てこられたのだ。
I'm only able to emerge like this now
because their chakra is finally one.
Going back to the jutsu
you mentioned earlier,
(ミナト)…で あなたが先ほど
言われた術のことですが→
具体的には
どのようにするのですか？
just what exactly are you doing to do?
術の印は わしがやる。
I will weave the signs for the jutsu.
ただ この術には
膨大なチャクラがいる。
But this jutsu requires
a vast amount of chakra…
わしには今
そのチャクラがない。
which I don't have right now
since I've given it away.
渡してしまった。
あまり時間もない
わしの言うとおりにしてくれ。
There's very little time.
I ask you to just do as I say.
THE TWO OF THEM…ALWAYS
This man lent me his power.
That's how we were able to get here.
(サクラ)この人が
力を貸してくれたの。
だから たどり着けた。
(サスケ)こいつが？
He did?
(オビト)うう！
いけない！
Oh no…
《クソ こいつらを
連れ帰るまでは…》
Damn it… I can't…
Not until I can bring them back…
しっかり！
Hang on!
《俺はまた 約束を
守ることができないのか？
Will I…
break my promise again?
リン…》
Rin?
((リンが 俺を
救ってくれるってことは つまり。
You know, Rin, you saving me,
is really the same as you
saving the world.
それは世界を救うってことと
同じなんだよな。
Hmm?
(リン)え？
だって ほら。
I mean…
俺は火影になって
この戦争を終わらせるわけだろ。
It's because I'm gonna become
the Hokage and end this war!
それには 俺が
この世に元気でいないと。
For me to do that I have to
stay strong and healthy in this world.
それにはやっぱ
なんて言うの？
So…how do I put it?
俺のこと ずっと
側で見ておいてくれないと。
If you don't stay close
and keep an eye on me…
つまり その…。
I mean…
Well…
うわ！
え？
Y-You got so close all of a sudden!
だ だって いきなり
近すぎるからさ！
びっくりしちまうだろ！
Don't scare me like that!
側で見ておいてくれって
言ったでしょ ウフフ。
You just said to stay close
and keep an eye on you?
Yeah, I did.
ああ 言ったさ
見ててくれ。
So watch over me.
俺は うちはの紋章を背負って
必ず火影になるんだ！
I'm going to wear the Uchiha crest…
and definitely become the Hokage!
うん！
Okay!
《やべえ やべえ やべえ！
Oh man, oh man, oh man!
This is the one day I can't be late!
今日だけは
遅刻するわけにはいかねえんだ》
NINJA ACADEMY
ENTRANCE CEREMONY
頑張るぞ！
これから楽しみだよね。
どこ行く どこ行く？
- Where do you wanna go?
- I don't know, where should we go?
はあ。
(カカシ)入学式から遅刻か。
む！
It's the entrance ceremony
and you're already late.
そんなやつに
アカデミーに入る資格はない。
Someone like you has no business
being in the Academy.
無理だな。
(リン)大丈夫よ。
You'll never make it.
It's okay.
これ ちゃんと
もらっておいたから。
I got this just for you.
お 俺の？
(リン)ええ。
For me?
Yes! Just submit this
and you'll be able to enroll.
この書類を出せば
問題なく入学できるって。
助かった 恩に着るぜ！
Thank you! You're a lifesaver!
(カカシ)甘やかしてっと
こいつの遅刻癖なおんねえぞ。
Keep pampering him and
he'll never be cured of his tardiness.
Shut up! Do you wanna fight?
(オビト)うるせえ！ やるか この！
始め！
Begin!
そこまで！
Stop right there!
うわ～！
かっこいい！
That's amazing!
お前 その額あては…。
What's with that headband?
You passed!
合格したのね おめでとう。
あぁ。
Congratulations!
Thanks.
なんだ 祝ってくれないのか。
Aren't you going to congratulate me?
As if! I'll catch up to you in no time!
誰が！
すぐに追いついてやるからな。
Just you wait!
覚えてろ！
オビト…。
Obito…
授業が始まるよ 行こう。
Class is starting. Let's go.
リン。
Rin…
俺を… 俺を見ててくれよな。
Keep…
Keep watching over me, okay?
え？
Huh?
俺… あいつに追いつくから。
I…
I'll catch up to him!
そんで 追い抜いて→
Then I'll surpass him and
必ず火影になるから！
I'll become the Hokage,
no matter what!
うん。 大丈夫 ちゃんと見てるよ。
Don't worry,
I'll always be watching.
あっ 見つけた オビト！
I found you, Obito!
あ？ リン！
Huh? Rin!
うわっ。
あっ！
イテテ…。
大丈夫!?
Are you all right?!
ハハハ… ちょっと滑っちまった。
大丈夫 大丈夫。
I just slipped.
I'm okay. I'm okay.
卒業証書 うちはオビト。
Here is the graduation certificate
for Obito Uchiha!
木ノ葉隠れ忍者アカデミーの
卒業を証する。
This certifies that you have graduated
from the Hidden Leaf Ninja Academy.
それと 雨の日も風の日も→
You are commended for persevering
through the rain and wind
よくここまで
修業と努力を続けました。
to reach this milestone!
はい 卒業おめでとう。
Here! Congratulations on graduating.
リン…。
Rin!
ありがとう リン。
Thank you, Rin.
みんないねえけど→
No one's here to watch.
火影のじいちゃんに渡されるより
ずっと嬉しいや。
But this makes me happier than
receiving it from Grandpa Hokage!
配属も決まったし
忍としての第一歩だぜ。
We've been assigned
to a team and now…
this is our first step as shinobi!
先はまだ長えけど→
I still have a long ways to go,
ちょっとは
火影に近づけた… よな？
but I'm a little bit closer to
becoming the Hokage…right?
ヘヘッ。
CHUNIN EXAMS
FIRST STAGE TEST
I'M ALWAYS WATCHING YOU.
-RIN
CHUNIN EXAMS
THIRD STAGE
ONE-ON-ONE BATTLES
この間のお返しは
たっぷりさせてもらうからな。
I'm going to have you pay me back
in full for the last time.
(ガイ)この間って…。
The "last time"?
Do your best, Obito!
頑張って オビト！
All right… Just watch me!
よし 見ててくれ！
Begin!
始め！
え？
Wha—?!
ホァチャー！
ぐはっ！
The winner is Might Guy!
勝者 マイト・ガイ！
What is he doing?
なにやってんだか。
スー ハァー。
So this is where you are.
こんなとこにいたんだ。
うわっ。 な なんだ リンか。
O-Oh, it's you, Rin.
カカシが受かるのは当然だけど
私たちもできるよ きっと。
It's only natural that Kakashi passed.
But we can do it too.
I know we can!
来年の試験 頑張りましょう。
Let's practice hard for next year!
でもよ カカシ見てると
なんだか やる気が出なくて。
But it's hard to get pumped up
after watching Kakashi…
What are you saying?!
なに言ってるの！
You're going to be the Hokage,
aren't you?
火影になるんでしょ？
私が ちゃんと見てるから。
I'm always watching you!
Okay!
ああ！
NINJA ACADEMY
オビト？
Obito…
ニッ！
やったぜ！ 俺も中忍だ！
I did it!
I'm a Chunin now!
You're late again!
(カカシ)またまた遅刻だよ お前は！
A lot happened on my way here
and I got lost…
いや 途中いろいろあって
道に迷っちゃってさ。
お前の歩く道は
いつも どんだけ➡
How come every path you take
is a roundabout route?
曲がりくねってるってのよ
ほんと！
Just walk a straight line!
They're not falling into line at all,
are they?
なかなか 足並みが揃わないね。
That's for sure.
But you know, Sensei…
確かに。 でもね 先生。
そこは私に任せて。
Let me handle this.
私が２人をちゃんと。
I'll watch over the two
of them…always!
Let's go…
(行くよ。 ２人とも！))
…you guys!
(オビト)意地っ張りで そのくせ
小さなことで一喜一憂する俺を→
I was stubborn and never at ease.
キミはいつでも助けてくれたのに…。
But you never failed to
come to my rescue.
Since it's a dream,
everything is how you want it!
((ゼツ : 夢だから
なんだって思いどおり。
(ゼツ)死んだ人だって
生きてることにできる。
Even the dead can be alive again!
A world of only victors…
(マダラ)勝者だけの世界
平和だけの世界→
A world of only peace…
A world of only love…
愛だけの世界
それらだけの世界をつくる。
I will create such a world.
Rin… again…
(リン… もう一度 もう一度
キミのいる世界をつくろう))
I'll create a world where
we can be together again.
よかった。 戻ったんですね。
Thank goodness!
You came back!
うっ…。
There's still something I must do.
まだ成すべきことがあるからな。
戻るぞ ２人とも。
We're going back, you two.
俺の体に触れておけ。
Hang on to me.
All right!
はい。
(ゼツ)やっぱり そうだよ。
There's no mistake.
《ナルト : あれは！ 前に
影分身が やられちまった…》
Those things…
They cut down
the Shadow Clones earlier.
The Clones are desperately
protecting that one.
(ゼツ)分身が 必死で守ってる。
間違いないよ 母さん。
There's no mistake, Mother.
背中に 求道玉を持ってるのが
本体だ。
The one with the Truthseeker Orbs
behind him is the real one!
無限かよ！
There's no end to them!
《俺は ただ見ているだけで
何もできないのか？
Am I powerless to do
anything but watch?
今頃 サクラもオビトも 必死で…。
Right now, even Sakura and Obito
are desperately…
俺は…。
I…
お前たちの師として→
I really couldn't do much
for you as your teacher.
たいしたことは
してやれなかった。
Nor you, Obito and Rin…
オビト… そして リン。
友としても 同じだ。
as your friend.
I just put on airs
because I was an elite,
エリートぶって 口先だけの
失敗ばかりを繰り返してきた》
and kept making mistakes.
まだ まだ！
It's not over yet!
ぜってぇ～
負けるわけにはいかねえんだ！
There's no way I'm gonna lose!
うぉ～っ！
《カカシ : ナルトが頑張ってるときに
何を感傷に浸ってるんだ!?
What am I doing wallowing,
when Naruto's fighting so hard?
だから ダメなんだ。
That's why I'm never any good.
今の俺でも
まだ やれることはあるはずだ》
There should be something
I can still do!
オビト！
Obito!
バカな！ サスケだと!?
Impossible!
It's Sasuke!
来た！
He's here!
(カグヤ)これで もう心配いらぬ。
Now, there's nothing to worry about.
まさか…。
ナルト！
No way!
Naruto!
Why you!
こ… こいつ！
He passed the Truthseeker Orbs
to a clone?
(ゼツ)分身に
求道玉を持たせてやがったのか！
We fell for something so simple!
こんな簡単なことに…。
ありがとうな サクラちゃん！ オビト！
Thank you, Sakura and Obito!
なに… 大丈夫だったの？
びっくりさせやがる！
What? You're okay?
You scared us there!
Sasuke!
サスケ！ ちゃんと
サクラちゃんとオビトに 礼言ったか？
Did you thank
Sakura and Obito properly?
敵に集中しろ。
Focus on the enemy!
《まぁ ナルトは昔から
意外に賢いからな》
Well, Naruto was always
unexpectedly cunning.
母さん。
Mother…
あいつらが
揃ったのならしかたない。
Since they've reunited,
we have no other choice.
もう チャクラを出し惜しみしている
場合じゃないよ。
We can't afford to be stingy
with our chakra.
わかっている。
I know that.
うわっ。
《体が重い。
My body feels so heavy.
この地面 体がくい込む》
This terrain…
is digging into my body!
これじゃ 浮けねえ。
I can't levitate!
《今度は 超重力の空間。
A heavy gravity plane this time!
だが… やつも同じように》
Except…
She's affected too.
くっ。
まずい。
Oh no!
《クソッ まだ左目の瞳力が》
Damn it! The Visual Prowess
in my left eye hasn't…
かわせ サスケ。
Dodge it, Sasuke!
重さで狙いが狂うかい？
Is the heavy gravity distorting your aim?
今ので調節した 次は当たる。
I've now adjusted for it.
I won't miss with the next one.
させるか！ うっ…。
I won't let you!
《俺にも まだできることはある》
There's something that I can still do.
《２人の盾に
なることくらいなら》
I can at least be a shield for them!
間に合え。
– Let me make it in time!
(２人)リン。
– Rin!
《キミはまた…》
Again, you…
《ありがとう リン。
Thank you, Rin.
俺も オビトも
そろそろ そっちへ行くよ。
Obito and I will be joining you soon.
また３人で ゆっくり話をしよう》
We can catch up then…
together, the three of us.
《リン 今度はあの世で→
Rin…
This time, when I get there…
少し俺と
２人きりの時間を過ごそう》
Let's spend some alone time together,
just you and me.
《カカシは邪魔だ。
Kakashi would just be in the way.
ここに置いていくよ》
I'm gonna leave him here.
《これは 神威》
This is…Kamui!
オビト お前！
Obito! You!
カカシ お前は当分こっちにいろ。
Kakashi… You stay here
a little while longer.
すぐに来んじゃねえぞ。
Don't you rush to follow us!
After fighting you,
I feel like I've woken up.
When I was a kid, I'd imagine myself
as the Hokage so often.
I think it's because
you brought back…
that indescribable feeling of
exhilaration and uncertainty.
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
"You Better…"
Don't laugh at Obito!